so morning good afternoon and good
evening to everybody thank you again for
um joining this week's magnet seminars
and for those who haven't um um
attended nfd seminars before we have
presentations which are about 30 minutes or so
in in length and we ask that you keep your
microphone muted um during the presentation
so as not to disturb uh the speaker and if you
are having any problems with your connection
and please if you turn off your video that can
help improve performance and at the end of the
session i will have a 10-15 minute uh question
and discussion uh session and your will invite
you to unmute to ask your questions but if
you don't want to to ask a question in person
you can type it into the chat and either
myself or one of the other conveners will
uh read out the questions for you uh as always
many of us are still uh working from home so
if you do have to to go and by all means um just
go it's not a problem and as i said the seminars
are being recorded we'll put the recording on
our youtube channel for people who can't attend
uh and at the end of the session um we'll have a
chance for a bit of a catch up a little bit of a
social um for anybody who's interested in hanging
around for for five or ten minutes and this part
of the the seminar isn't actually um recorded
so today i'm really pleased to say that we have
uh yuji yamamoto from kochi university and
today uh yamamoto-san will be talking about the
shaw pd intensity method of being applied to age
aged trms so i will hand over to you yamamoto
okay thank you very much for providing me over
opportunity to present our talk
okay i'll start the screen sharing
okay i hope everybody can see my screen
share actually today thank you so much
actually today's talk is the uh authored talk
uh together with lisa talks and hong song
and christine and santos and the title is like
that this is a kind of companion study of the aged
trm investigation by editorial message by
talks it was which is recently published
and using the sister specimen i
apply the snake show method and
i we are now in preparation for the
manuscript and almost i think almost i have
my script is just almost done but
this is still uh before a submission
so it so it would be very good if you
could provide uh many comments for us to
improve is uh uh some improve the
manuscript before pub uh before submission
uh first of all i would like to start with
some free some backgrounds so this right is uh
uh example behavior of arrived plots
in response to stereotype method uh
so you everybody knows that if blocking
temperature and unblocking temperature is equal
arrivals is linear but there is a lot of cases for
violation of this equation for example if unbroken
temperature is below broken temperature have
already brought curves and this curvature can be a
it can be characterized several parameters but
most most recently used index is k parameter by
greg k is for entire interval and k
prime k prime is for selected interval
and in santosa talks 2019 uh they
used a very several a variety of
volcanic rocks and they investigated the
easy terry experiments in response to fresh
natural remote mobilization and pressure of drm
top pro is the arrival obtained for the
nrm of various various volcanic rocks
so based on the k index if
threshold was set as 0.164
these two behavior is categorized as straight
alright and these two types are categorized as
carved plots after uh after application
of the agitatory method on nrm
they heated the samples in
laboratory to import fresh raw drm
immediately after imparting the
pressure of drm it means the h0h
they repeated the digital experiments and
they categorized the result according to this
index and they found that this is
straight this these are curved they were
these were straight and these were cupped
it means that there are santos and talks
concludes that these 20 samples
could be classified as four types
in our infrastructure pressure of drm for straight
in our infrastructure inflation of drm for craft
nrm for carved and fresh love theory for straight
nrrm for carved and fresher of drn also for carved
uh they they further investigated
the laboratory theorem behavior on the on
this rock on these samples uh in toxic or 2021
firstly specimens were prepared like that
actually this is the sample which were
investigated in santosa talks 2019 which is
presented in the previous slide for the sample
laboratory aging was done for uh several
orientation and two types of robbery field
and two years these are the a these are this is
a schematic diagram showing how aging was done
so actually that this zero degree means that
the fraction of tearing direction and the aging
direction is the same this 45 direction means that
this aging laboratory field was applied for 45
degree depressure from the original threshold
of trm for two years and in talks at our 2021
they uprising egyptery method for specimens with
position one three and five and when having the
look according to the four sun for some prototype
behavior you mean that these types of behavior
they found that their curvatures generally
increased for aged trm except for uh yes and they
keep point key points of that paper that
there are this increase of curvatures
are probably due to unequal blocking and
unblocking temperature spectrum and this
inequality grows through time it means that this
equality growed for two years that's why the
curvature increased for aged trm compared to
the fresh pre first year means uh zero age
http means two years age
so so from this right that this is the
main topic of this today's contents so
uh i we heard uh we have a opportunity to
apply it's an accounting method uh which is a
one variant of the showtive method
to this type of aged samples
so for 20 specimens of these aged samples
we applies our subcultural method and
obtained results were analyzed by a python code
according to these steps so as
a at this stage i skipped the
detail express a little explanation of this
so uh probably many people are not so familiar
with the snake also method so i'd like to explain
an outline of the procedure firstly nrm was
subjected to low temperature democratization after
ltd stepwise afd and measurement were repeated
after completion of the progress a
progressive af democratization of nrm and then
we import laboratory arm to the samples so
when importing arm applied field direction
is in parallel to nrm direction and same cycles
are repeated after that we heated samples
at above curie temperature to import
full trm so in many cases the uh
is the highest security temperature so we usually
set the maximum heating temperature as a six step
so after by this heating uh first robot
trm uh can be achieved we call this as trm1
the same cycle is repeated and after
that we for we again impart the arm
by the same same dc field as arm 0 and also the
apply imparting direction is in parallel to the
robot trm direction after
completion of demonetization of arm1
the sample is again heated above query temperature
on the same laboratory field but longer time
for example if the first laboratory
heating was down for 20 minutes
more than 20 minutes for heating for
like 30 minutes or 40 minutes and the
choice of that time is based on is depending on
the laboratory setting as some laboratory can uh
it is necessary to uh long long longer
uh heating time for some robotic setting
and other laboratory setting shorter heating
may be enough for importing through dra
after that second trm is obtained we call
this a trm2 same cycle repeated and also
the arm is again imported uh this a fly
imparting dc field for arm is the same
and the apply inverting direction of
arm is in parallel to the rubber array
so by doing that we can we we can correct
not only the possible thermal alternate
thermal alteration inventory but also the
air uh any therapy of demand magnetization
before before presenting the main results
i would like to make some emphasis on
how how ltd is useful so
this is an example diagram
these are the jesus uh from different samples
i mean the different examples mean that
not aged samples this is already published
result in japanese volcanic clocks
as you can see that there is some reduction in
nrm by lte and we can recognize some deduction
also in all cellular vector probes
and same is true for the arm
we can we can observe the sum reduction in
cosmetic spectra led after ltd and without ltd
so we think that the ltd is particularly useful
to isolate primary direction
from traditional direction
these are the three examples it's not
yet published but it's from there from
icelandic lovers uh which a i and
maxwell brown are jointly working on
so these all of these are traditional directions
because uh this this these also approach are in uh
geographic coordinates it means this is
they are they are usual zeida belt probes
so in iceland in iceland normal
and reverse period should have
very steep inclination but you can recognize that
the inclination component is very low very shallow
so for these samples ltd drastically
demagnetize the secondary components so the
ltd help to isolate primary direction
because in conjunction with progressive afd
and this is an another this is an
another type expression how ltd is useful
uh this diagram is from cotesy of dr
simula yoshimura it was presented the
parentheses result from ethiopian levels and when
we compare the mrs over mms parameters versus a
rt demagnetized fraction for initial for arm
before heating so we can you can see that the
i mean lesser uh smaller number
of this index it means a kind of
so inclusion or kind of
multi-domain like components uh is
now also samples with closer magnetic grain
show tendency to largely
reduction in in response to ltd
okay let's move to the main topic uh
as i previously presented the
present specimens were categorized
into four types svs sc cs and cc
according to the easy terrier results
if uh keeping in mind uh of these catego these
categories uh i would like to explain that it's
not also result according to the uh classification
by toxic dwarf 2021 this is an example from ss
type specimen this is the nrm bus has collected
trm1 product and this is the first crm1 versus
a collected theorem too these diagrams
are these diagrams were generated from
these two diagrams and these two diagrams this
is the original nrn and trm1 diagram this is the
arm0 and arm1 diagram so by using
the relation between arm 0 and arm 1
we can we collect this theorem 1 and we
can and correct the tremor can be obtained
and we could find a very good linear portion
and this did result in a 17.8 microtester
so this is very close to the laboratory field feet
which was used for imparting elaborate refresh tlm
and
there is almost very small curvatures were
observed and this is the second heating plot
using arm1 and arm2 relation for collecting
tlm2 and this is the collective drm-2
this is an example result from ac type of behavior
the they are also good and we could obtain very
a very good very accurate parenthesis
estimate curvatures were also not so large
this is a cs type result uh interesting
point is that we recognize some curvatures
so this is tier nrm bus of trm1 and this
is arm 0x01 and curvatures are very similar
so corrected diagram there we can find
the linear portion and this linear portion
this linear portion resulted in reasonable
estimate of six eight point two micro tester
for the second heating the
curvatures were not observed
and for this sample
reduction of arm 0 by ltd is 7.7 percent so
most striking example is a cc type result so
curvature so for for this particular uh result
curvatures were not so large but you you can
see that the reduction by ltd is relatively
large compared with the previous results
so we could find the linear
portion which he gave not about
api estimate absolute parenthesis estimate
so this is the this is the bar approach uh for
absolute valentine's day from all specimens and uh
lut demonetized arms zero fraction and the red
horizontal axis indicates the individual samples
so you can see that three results were
rejected which means desired results
were not satisfying the selection criteria
and this solid line indicates a laboratory
field for imparting fresh drm this means the 770
700 micro tesla if the parentheses estimation is
successful
ideally 17.0 micro tesla should be obtained so
and these different colors are for
uh stand for different categories
which is defined which was defined
in talks thunderstorm talks 2019
so because we can think that this one example
is an outlier if we exclude if we excluded this
particular result mean and median and the standard
deviations are these these are very close to the
actual field of 70
microtesla and the interesting point is that the
reduction by ltd is larger for cs and cc type
samples compared with ss and ac type samples
so this these bar plots are the curvature for
inner empty element diagram and arm 0 element
diagram these are these are uh these
are this value is for example this is
the curvature from nrmt element diagram this
is a curvature of arm 0 l1 diagram like that
ah like that this is the curvature entire
curvature not not k5 but k entire curvature of the
diagram this is a nrn bossa trm1 this is the arm
0 versus arm1 you can see that the larger curve
there is a tendency that larger curvatures are
large for cs and cg types samples compared with
ss and sd type samples and the second interesting
point is that the curvatures are smeared
between n or mtr1 and arm0ir1 this this similarity
can be recognized in this vibrate this is a
curvature for in our theory one diagram and this
is the curvature in arm zero l1 diagram we can
recognize the linear relationship it means that
the carbon curvatures are observed in two diagrams
particularly for cs and cc specimens but because
of the similarity of the curvature arm correction
was worked well to result in a linear
uh inner emptier in one step diagram
for obtaining value intensity
and firstly we expected that the ltd can ltd
could eliminate a curvature what actually is
even after the ltd we recognize curvature in
nrm tlman diagram and arm 0 erroneous diagram
so when compared we see how much
lt demagnetize deflection of arm 0
there may be some relationship but the statistic
state statistically speaking has no relationship
so let's move to the comparison between
absolute valentine's day by the agitarium method
and the telecast method because the present
the present is present synagogue method was
applied to their sister specimens of the study by
talksetter 2021 we can compare uh the ts uh api
by the cultural method and api by easy method
for for each sample and as i previously
presented eg3 method was applied for nrm
flash laboratory trm and edge the trm for
three different positions so except for the nrm
we can we can make a comparison and these four
diagrams that are compares a compared result
so it's difficult uh so so first of all we can say
that no no discernable relationship in these plots
and second point is that the
range range of the ap resulted resultant
api so for for example that this first plot
uh vertical axis indicates the api obtained by
the cultural method so except for that one outlier
we can say that the range of the api estimate
by the telecast method is between 65 and 75
and for eg3 method for fresh drm there is also
the one outlier so apart from this outer layer
the range of the api by digitally method is also
65.75 it means that's the celebration method
and refresh your about the trm of by
easy terry method for easy television are
almost equivalent quality but
if having a look of the aged trm
uh range of the api estimate is wider for example
the position one sample this is 63 to 83 like that
it it means that it implies that the aging
aiding seemed to result in a
wider range of the api in that
easy television but it's
not for or it's not method
and this is i think this is the final slide of
final slide showing the interesting experimental
results we compare the lt demographic reflection
of arm0 internal cultural method versus easy curve
curvature observed in the ri
diagram in by the egyptery method
there are there are five plots and
vertical axis indicates the lt demagnetized
production of ar m0 in the circulation method
and horizontal axis indicates the curvature
this is a k not k prime not k prime
i arrive so k curvature k in the right in the
original trm original term means nrm this is the
first theorem first tlu means zero hd laboratory
theory and this age the theorem was of two years
age to tra so in all approach uh so i'd like
to i'd like to summarize our talk uh we applied
the structure method to 10 specimens in aged
interruptive for two years a total of 17 apis were
successfully obtained as resulting on an overall
average of 69.3 with a standard deviation of 2.7
lte demonetized fraction of arm
roger is a cs and cc type samples
down in the css and sc type samples and
curvatures were observed in the nrn thermal
fluids and the arm0iron approach even after lted
and they were larger in the cs and cc categories
that in the css and ac categories but the
curvatures in the two blocks of similar
resulting in straight uh nrm and masses
collected dll1 plots by air inflection
apis by the eg3 method were previously
obtained from system specimens
and this api did not show any discernible
relationship with apis by the ts method and the
api range the api range become wider by aging in
the eg3 method while the ts method resulted in the
range almost equivalent to that by the egyptery
method on fresh drms in spite of the aging
and everything democratized function of arms 0 in
the telecast method raja for example is the raja
aeg curvature so remains carrier physical it is
mainly originated from the magnetic crystalline
isotropy probably perhaps susceptible for
time growth of an equality between blocking
and numbering temperature spectra which has been
suggested for cause of the easy curvatures okay so
this is the all thank you for listening uh thank
you yamamoto very very interesting presentation
thank you very much there is a
big round of applause for you
um so now we are happy to take questions for
yamamoto-san yes um andrei has one question
you cannot mute yourself
hi youtube it's great to see you oh and yes
um i would like to to ask if you did you check
the the campa the composition of your samples
prior to the experiments because uh if you have
magnetized magnetite with true magnetite with
cool temperature 580 and the verb transition it's
one story if you have titanic let's say titanium
magnetite without the verb transition it will be
oh it will also response to ltd but in a different
way did you check that or did you make sure that
all your samples have is the same composition ah
thank you for your point it's a good point that
andrew actually uh we did uh actually i did not
confirm that all the samples are sold is a
magnetite uh we need to check the composition
yes absolutely because uh basically basically
what would happen if you have uh let's say a
little bit uh you you would need to separate the
uh the contribution from different grain sizes
from from that of composition obviously
okay yeah great thank you thank you so much
thank you for your question and thanks
yamamoto-san for answering the question
is anybody else some questions and comments
i actually if anyone else has a uh
question i have i have uh one sure okay
i mean i guess just looking at your comparison of
the izzy and and um the shaw method i guess you
know the fact that you you can see a much wider
spread of results in izzy than than with the show
if you sort of exclude that one one outlier i
mean that kind of implies that the aging has um
a much stronger effect on on blocking
temperature than it does on on coercivity um
you know i don't know if you want to maybe make
a you know a comment or some thoughts on that
in terms of what that might mean um for um
for magnetic samples in general actually
so my general impression is that there are yes
so aging impact is a big in blocking temperature
space as long in the classification space so
my impression that the uh such an equality in a
blocking and unblocking according to age can be a
efficiently removed a combination by lted and afd
so i i have one slice
uh these are
so in talks at 2021 uh they investigated
a series of rock magnetic parameters
using a series of folk diagrams and i tried to
compare uh uh if if in periodicity resulted by the
cultural method for the arrogant parameters may
mainly obtained by the hysteresis measurement uh
but no discernable uh relationships
are harmed did jesus api estimates
browsers six different hysteresis parameters and
this is the curvature in the nrd armor approach
after ltd internal cultural method uh versus
electromagnetic parameters so ah but this this
is the uh this ignore this curvature in our mtr
membranes were obtained after a post ltd reminisce
so i i think so so it's so at the moment
sir it's a difficult to say anything
from these electromagnetic parameters
but my impression is a combination of ltd
and air democratization is very effective
to eliminate the bad effect in time
growth in between blocking and unblocking
okay thank you did greg answer your question
yeah yeah i also have another quick question
um yeah so essentially we've got um
three main fields directions the nrm
the uh aged uh aging field direction and
then the um laboratory field direction um
what is what is the relationship between the nrm
field direction and the trm lab trm direction
sorry i i haven't fully considered about
these points so it's a good point but
i think this is the first design
of the whole study by eliza
thank you um thank you and i think
shibuya-san because yeah yeah just just i want
to know the uh environment of the uh storage
i i mean that some not only the magnetic field
but temperature or humidity or other any nucleus
for that two years aging it was done in
ambient temperature so i think there is
a can shows a a photograph of the aging
environment so this is the in the ordinary
a laboratory space so there i think there
is there was no control for humidity
yeah just just the the different uh
the the the the difference of the uh uh
show me show that method and the stereotype
method is that uh show type is full tlm and
and the uh stereotype is partial trm and so
the uh full trm is good for the comparison
but the problem is they're always fully armed
we we have to think about chemical difference
the chemical or changing that but in this
case that all the sample is already heated in
laboratory that's a good point so all 20 specimens
were stabilized for tamil hiding it should be but
still still it's changing so it's very
complicated but so the is does it do do we
uh apply these results to the uh ancient rocks or
the weathered rocks that can do do you have any
opinion about that oh thank you timothy this
is a good point now one uh but what point of
a shortage of the show is uh intense heating
above curie temperature it sometimes or more
or less change the chemical composition so on
such here such a large a alteration such a large
a changing in chemical point composition it
cannot be compensated by the arm collection so
so laboratory heating in the showtime method
should be much considered we should improve that
try to suppress the robot alteration by heating in
the showtime person this is uh one important point
and yeah we we have microwave heating
should be one choice but it's still honda
another point is that the full trm is better
for the hero intensity estimate so that but your
results show that the uh show type methods are
a little bit better than that stereotype method
in this time so which is a chemically a stable
environment show that method is better than that
method is that this result seems reasonable
for me reasonable okay thank you sir so i agree
with you that's uh for ideal samples stereotype
method should be the best but particularly for
four rock samples there is more worries on
ideality and one one one which i think is the
one major and ideology is just the magnetostatic
interaction among magnetic grains in samples
so so acquisition of fruity already laboratory
can mimic the natural cooling process so it means
heating above kill temperature and cool down
it mimics the natural process so even though
there is some magnetostatic disruption among
grains such interaction can be reproduced by a a
one one time heating in the showtime method
yeah yeah i agree okay thank you i can maybe
add the information that i was in in lisa's lab
and i saw the samples with my eyes and they
are stored in a double new metal box tube
inside the lab regarding humidity i'm not quite
sure but regarding temperature the temperature
is quite constant first because it's it's
inside the closed environment and second also
the outside temperature in california doesn't
change much at all so maybe that would kind of
limit a little bit the alterations hopefully
but it's still a very interesting question so
thank you very much um so we
have one question in the chat
uh by elisa um asking could the ltd have reduced
the range of api estimates in the easytalia method
it might be possible that so combination of
ltd with the teletype method is very time
consuming it means that so i think the so
at every heating step ltd should be upright
yes i have done it myself and it's a lot of time
additional time thank you thank you i
hope that answered lisa's questions um
simon i think do you want to admit yourself or
i can read up the oh yes do the research suggest
that the fraud
uh i think
more or less the fragile commercial can
be overcome using the showtive method
but one point should be considered is a
comment by andre ltd is ltd is effective
for magnetic composition but not so effective
for titanium-rich titan magnetic composition
yes thank you i it could be an interesting point
to to implement um what andrei said as well um
so thank you um if there are there aren't
any more questions we want to give another
big round of applause for yamamoto-san for the
great presentation thank you very much thank you
so much for everybody thank you and greg will
have some slides to share and then after the
slides you're welcome to stay for an informal
chat that won't be recorded so thank you all
thank you i'm also some for for a really
interesting talk a lot of things to think
about um in that presentation and i'm sure i'll
be uh dropping you an email with a few ideas and
thoughts to chat about um just before we we draw
this session to a close i'm just a reminder of our
schedule for for the rest of the year this was the
the last talk that we're going to be running in
an eu um eastern hemisphere time slot so for the
last remainder of the year we're going to go back
to a european uh america's time slot and we have
four more speakers lined up to take us through
the end of 2021 um and um we'll stop uh in
early december and we'll have a break over
the agu and uh and the christmas period um but
where we are um recruiting for our 2022 season
and we're encouraging everybody or anybody
who's interested in giving a presentation to
reach out to us um and we can make an arrangement
for for our next season and in particular we want
to encourage um ecr's early career researchers
to uh participate and also this is our
a reminder uh we have our our youtube channel
uh where all of the the magnets recordings uh
are are made available now unfortunately today
i had some technical difficulties um just before
the very end my computer crashed so we'll need to
see what uh what we have of a recording of today's
session hopefully we'll have uh enough to present
so my apologies if if if we don't have that um
we'll sort something out um so please um check out
our our youtube channel for all of our our videos
um and thank you everybody for for joining magnets